<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/e-books/nieuw-in-de-collectie.html</id>
    <title>Alle nieuwe e-books</title>
    <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:14.464Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/icod/bieb-feeds</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/e-books/nieuw-in-de-collectie.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://bieb-feeds.statichost.eu/feeds/nieuw.atom"/>
    <rights>Koninklijke Bibliotheek</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Godfried Danneels]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/397043317/godfried-danneels-karim-schelkens---j%C3%BCrgen-mettepenningen</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/397043317/godfried-danneels-karim-schelkens---j%C3%BCrgen-mettepenningen"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:17:58.837Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[biographie]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A397043317?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767251878463&sig=efb217a6f22491c1459e2ebf5ea316aaaa42888f7eb10f9b50c109c3f871bc07&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'Godfried Danneels'" title="Omslag van 'Godfried Danneels'">
<p>Godfried Danneels (1933) a incarné, au fil des décennies écoulées, le visage de l'Église en Belgique. Le parcours de vie de cet homme affable et énigmatique se déroule de Kanegem à Rome et bien au-delà. En tant que professeur, prêtre et prélat, Godfried Danneels a vécu de très près les changements intervenus dans notre société. Il est moins connu pour son rôle de diplomate ecclésiastique de haut rang. Ses biographes Karim Schelkens et Jürgen Mettepenningen ont dépouillé un trésor de documentation, ont interrogé des dizaines de témoins dont le chemin a croisé celui du cardinal et ont obtenu l'accès exclusif à ses archives privées. Il en résulte une image surprenante et critique d'un observateur privilégié de l'histoire de la Belgique et de l'Église universelle. </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Karim Schelkens</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Jürgen Mettepenningen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mi Biblia tiene un hilo rojo]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/401207064/mi-biblia-tiene-un-hilo-rojo-peter-van-olst</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/401207064/mi-biblia-tiene-un-hilo-rojo-peter-van-olst"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:17:59.250Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A401207064?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767251878978&sig=3217bbaa94687b85dfbdc2d671126fd1deeddeb2a8fa82f0ee9eac0d30121f21&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'Mi Biblia tiene un hilo rojo'" title="Omslag van 'Mi Biblia tiene un hilo rojo'">
<p>Con tu Biblia tienes puro oro en las manos. Es el oro de la revelación de Dios a los hombres, también a ti. Lamentablemente muchas veces no nos damos cuenta de esto. Ya la cerramos demasiado rápido – si es que la abrimos aún. El oro no se reconoce, no es valorado como tal. Este libro quiere ayudarte a estudiar los 66 libros de la Biblia y a descubrir su hilo rojo. El hilo rojo de Jesucristo. Para él se prepara lugar en el Antiguo Testamento; en el Nuevo Testamento te es presentado directamente. Fue prometido y vino. Él es el gran Contenido del libro de Dios. Peter van Olst estudió ciencias políticas y teología. Ocho años trabajó como periodista para un periódico cristiano en Holanda. Desde el 2005 es evangelista de la Misión Holandesa Maranatha en el Ecuador. </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Peter van Olst</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Homme versus machine]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/433305061/homme-versus-machine-geertrui-mieke-de-ketelaere</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/433305061/homme-versus-machine-geertrui-mieke-de-ketelaere"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:17:59.669Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[L’intelligence artificielle démystifiée]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A433305061?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1766854752330&sig=cf0924075735b9a2ec2fe13ea53ad33a538615b1ac0a14006a7190fdc4cd9df8&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'Homme versus machine'" title="Omslag van 'Homme versus machine'">
<p>Ceux qui pensent que l’intelligence artificielle (IA) est très éloignée de leur réalité se trompent. L’IA n’est pas réservée aux films de science-fiction futuristes ou aux salons technologiques branchés. L’IA est partout, y compris dans votre vie.  Le folder publicitaire personnalisé du supermarché avec des offres « rien que pour vous » ? IA.  Les chansons proposées sur Spotify ? IA.  Les feux de signalisation à réglage automatique au coin de la rue ? IA.  On ne peut le nier. L’intelligence artificielle s’insinue dans notre réalité à une vitesse vertigineuse. Elle se manifeste dans votre vie quotidienne, mais aussi dans les différents secteurs économiques. Cela soulève de nombreuses questions. Que peut faire l’IA ? Que ne peut-elle pas encore faire ? Et dans quelle mesure l’IA est-elle vraiment intelligente et apporte-t-elle une valeur ajoutée à notre mode de vie ?  Geertrui Mieke De Ketelaere, experte en IA, suit l’évolution de ce monde fascinant au premier rang. Dans ce livre, elle explique de manière accessible et transparente les concepts de base de l’intelligence artificielle. Elle ne se contente pas de souligner les nombreuses possibilités qu’offre l’IA, elle en épingle également les risques. De Ketelaere emmène le lecteur au-delà de l’engouement médiatique, afin qu’il puisse participer à ce débat fascinant tout en étant informé. Une chose est sûre : déjà très importante aujourd’hui, l’IA deviendra cruciale pour notre avenir.  </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Geertrui Mieke De Ketelaere</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ferien auf Texel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/433343257/ferien-auf-texel-linda-van-rijn</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/433343257/ferien-auf-texel-linda-van-rijn"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:00.190Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kriminalroman]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A433343257?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767223605028&sig=f55d0c72af04af1435890a0ded8c1d22c90411909c28f9a439b3f6412134caec&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'Ferien auf Texel'" title="Omslag van 'Ferien auf Texel'">
<p>Linda van Rijn ist eine niederländische Bestsellerautorin. Ihre Bücher stehen durchweg ganz oben auf der niederländischen Bestsellerliste und haben sich bereits über zwei Millionen Mal verkauft. Ferien auf Texel ist ihr dreiundzwanzigster Urlaubskrimi, der – ebenso wie Zoutelande – ins Deutsche übersetzt wurde. Ein Traum, der dank des Erbes, das Daniëlle von ihrer Oma erhalten hat, in Erfüllung gehen konnte. Während des ersten Sommers im eigenen Häuschen können sie ihr Glück kaum fassen. Das Wetter ist traumhaft schön, die Kinder spielen unermüdlich am Strand, und Gijs und Daniëlle genießen das Leben in vollen Zügen. Eines Abends taucht ein Besucher mit einer seltsamen Nachricht bei ihnen auf. Sie klingt bedrohlich. Ihrer Meinung nach kann es sich dabei nur um ein Missverständnis handeln und deshalb vergessen sie den Vorfall schnell wieder. Bis Daniëlle auf ihre alte Urlaubsliebe Mitchell trifft, der mehr über sie und ihre Familie zu wissen scheint, als ihr lieb ist... Die niederländische Presse über Ferien auf Texel: Ferien auf Texel ist ein überraschendes Buch, das ein reines Lesevergnügen bietet. Es ist eine flott geschriebene Geschichte, mit eindrucksvollen Charakteren und einer gut durchdachten, spannendenden Handlung. Linda van Rijns Schreibstil ist flüssig und leicht zu lesen, so wie wir es inzwischen von ihr gewohnt sind. Dadurch ist man sofort in der Geschichte drin und es ist fast unmöglich, Ferien auf Texel aus der Hand zu legen. </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Linda van Rijn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lieber Got. Drei Brüder im Ersten Weltkrieg]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/433100125/lieber-got--drei-bru-der-im-ersten-weltkrieg-bob-latten</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/433100125/lieber-got--drei-bru-der-im-ersten-weltkrieg-bob-latten"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:00.832Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A433100125?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767251880409&sig=39aad96557730f951e15d444d7710d7e5583a3ea6c5e7a850c6cd3aa4df981af&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'Lieber Got. Drei Brüder im Ersten Weltkrieg'" title="Omslag van 'Lieber Got. Drei Brüder im Ersten Weltkrieg'">
<p>'Lieber Gott. Niet alleen de tijd sneuvelt.' is het waargebeurde verhaal van de gegoede Duitse familie Lieber in oorlogstijd. In de strijd om de Vogezen, rond Verdun en bij de Somme sneuvelen drie van de vier broers. Hen verbindt een eenvoudig zakuurwerk. Na het sneuvelen van de een neemt de ander het mee het veld in. Totdat ook hij sneuvelt. De persoonlijke brieven van reserveluitenant Hyazinth Lieber, in het dagelijks leven advocaat, en de dagboekfragmenten van filosofiestudent en luitenant Theodor Lieber vormen, samen met de oorspronkelijke teksten uit regimentsgeschiedenissen en authentieke foto's een adembenemend tijdsbeeld.</p><p>Nauwgezet en minutieus  'Lieber Gott' is in een adem te noemen met Getuigen (Témoins), de eerste omvangrijke en systematische kritische studie naar ooggetuigenverslagen van de loopgravenstrijd en het standaardwerk van de Franse schrijver en oorlogsveteraan Jean Norton Cru (1879-1949).</p><p>- Prof. dr. Wim Klinkert, Nederlandse Defensie Academie en Universiteit van Amsterdam</p><p>Indrukwekkend  Bob Latten schrijft al jaren over die Grote Oorlog die aan Nederland voorbij ging. Door met hart en ziel te schrijven maakt hij het menselijke drama invoelbaar voor de lezer. 'Lieber Gott'maakt opnieuw indruk.  - Diederik van Vleuten, stand-up historian</p><p>Kleine weerspiegeling van een groot verdriet</p><p>'Lieber Gott. Niet alleen de tijd sneuvelt'is een boek over de drie Duitse, katholieke, conservatief-nationalistische broers Lieber die vol overtuiging de oorlog in gaan. Zij sneuvelen alle drie. Het maakt van dit boek een kleine weerspiegeling van het grote verdriet dat oorlog heet.'  - Leo van Bergen, autoriteit op het gebied van de gezondheidszorg in de Eerste Wereldoorlog</p><p>Adembenemend  Een opzienbarend, adembenemend en zeer aangrijpend boek, dat mij het gevoel gaf zelf deelnemer te zijn aan levensecht beschreven, somtijds gruwelijke gebeurtenissen. Een waargebeurde geschiedenis en een ontroerend monument voor drie broers, die uiteindelijk in de strijd hun einde vinden. Ik heb het in een ruk uitgelezen.  - Hans Andriessen, auteur van onder andere 'De oorlogsbrieven van Unteroffizier Carl Heller' </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Bob Latten</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daseinsrecht]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/437924327/daseinsrecht-maarten-a--oversier</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/437924327/daseinsrecht-maarten-a--oversier"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:01.428Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Licht in die verdrängte Geschichte, die wir noch in uns tragen]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A437924327?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767251880961&sig=78bc76ca9c5d8fc19f45620b9bd2a28904c4177a7a965f9613e2c9ed87b11c25&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'Daseinsrecht'" title="Omslag van 'Daseinsrecht'">
<p>Das Echo unverarbeiterer Traumata aus vergangenen Zeiten und sogar früheren Leben belastet den modernen Menschen - körperlich, seelisch oder emotional. Doch welche Entstehungsgeschichte steht wirklich hinter diesen Traumatisierungen? In seiner gut 25-jährigen Tätigkeit als Reinkarnations- und Rückführungstherapeut stellt Maarten Oversier fest, dass die Ursachen der Probleme seiner Klienten eigentlich immer in drei typischen Bereichen der Geschichte liegen: in schockierenden und darum oft verdrängten Erlebnissen unserer Vorfahren, in der Hölle zweier Weltkriege und in den dubiosen Normen und Zwängen der katholischen Kirche. Hinter diesen Einflüssen taucht das Dekor eines großangelegten Plans zur Knechtung Frage der Zeit, bis es unübersehbar werden wird: Die Lebenskraft der Erdenbürger lässt sich nicht dauerhaft im Zaum halten. Im Kosmos vollzieht sich ein enormer Bewussteinswandel und genau deshalb sind derzeit so viele inkarnierte Seelen auf der Erde. Verflochten mit den Fallbeispielen von Klienten, die von ihren frappanten Heilungsprozessen berichten, veranschaulicht Maarten, wie unsere onvollendete Vergangenheit unaufhaltsam bis in unsere Gegenwart durchsickert. Aber er erklärt auch, wie Traumatisierungen erkannt, verarbeitet und damit entkräftet werden können. Sein Motto: "Die wertvollsten Entdeckungen macht, wer ausgetretene Pfade verlässt." DASEINRECHT lässt uns an ergreifenden Geschichten teilhaben, liest sich manchmal wie das spannende Drehbuch eines Films und hat das Potenzial, Weltbilder zu revolutionieren. Auch hochaktuelle Themen wie Organspende, die Corona-Krise und Transhumanismus werden ohne Scheu besprochen. </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Maarten A. Oversier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Witching moor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/375581413/witching-moor-mariette-aerts</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/375581413/witching-moor-mariette-aerts"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:02.023Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A375581413?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767251881574&sig=6bebb6daa705d339ea4f0a1432f82f1b99b1ef4c53ff0fc677b33f2cd070d485&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'Witching moor'" title="Omslag van 'Witching moor'">
<p>"Karim and Lena know better not to cross the moors, even though it is a shortcut, because it is commonly known that those moors are haunted by witches. Somewhere deep inside the Haunted Moors a dark secret is hidden. But Karim and Lena want to know what happened to their classmate Rennie, who disappeared so suddenly last summer. What is the truth about the white witch and what happened at the old water mill in ancient times? Who is the lady with the long, white hair and blank eyes and why is she calling so desperately for Lena? Then, one day, a fearsome face appears in the water, lights hover above the moors at night, and Karim and Lena are about to receive a whole lot more answers than they bargained for"</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Mariette Aerts</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Armin only]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394693922/armin-only-coen-bom</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394693922/armin-only-coen-bom"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:02.936Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A394693922?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767251882161&sig=3ee6a60e70993ad8d6fee0b1895aae6c2718487e12c8e0dc951acdfb24905592&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'Armin only'" title="Omslag van 'Armin only'">
<p>In 2008 werd Armin van Buuren bij de verkiezingen van 's werelds beste 100 dj's uitgeroepen tot populairste dj van de wereld. Het boek Eén op één volgt hem in het jaar dat daaraan voorafging. Van Buuren wordt gevolgd tijdens zijn talloze vliegreizen, optredens en interviewsessies. Het is de eerste inkijk in het leven de populairste dj van het moment. Wat gebeurt er nu werkelijk buiten het vele vliegen en alle glitter & glamour? Hoe is Armin op nummer 1 gekomen? Aan het woord komen zijn vrienden, ouders en manager(s). Met vele exclusieve foto's. </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Coen Bom</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Personal leadership]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394708121/personal-leadership-marieta-koopmans</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394708121/personal-leadership-marieta-koopmans"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:03.439Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A394708121?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767238309314&sig=0c49b2f44b797fce0379a92d54aebe223438a40e98455d699e46d78beead33ac&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'Personal leadership'" title="Omslag van 'Personal leadership'">
<p>Professional leadership starts with personal leadership. What is your vision of leadership? Which values do you find important? What do you believe about yourself? How do you think companies should be managed? All these questions relate to personal leadership. This book will help you to discover and give shape to your own management style. Using the Quinn model you will be able to look into which management role is appropriate for you. With the Ofman core qualities model you will be able to discover your qualities, your shortcomings, challenges and the things you are allergic to. You will work on effective leadership using the seven Covey characteristics, and you will learn how to manage your time using the MBTI (Myers-Briggs Type Indicator). Stress is tackled as well as any convictions you have that hamper your progress. So that finally you gain an insight into what is necessary for any good professional: an image of yourself as a manager and the image you want to project in the future. </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Marieta Koopmans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Career management via LinkedIn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394593022/career-management-via-linkedin-aaltje-vincent---jacco-valkenburg</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394593022/career-management-via-linkedin-aaltje-vincent---jacco-valkenburg"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:03.974Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[using your online network to find new work or challenging assignments]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A394593022?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767251883550&sig=226a06c9f3899722cb245d49afb6f75a516321c484dfda07fb0668026deb8c80&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'Career management via LinkedIn'" title="Omslag van 'Career management via LinkedIn'">
<p>Networking is the way for finding new work. And this is done more and more online. LinkedIn has become an enormously popular network for maintaining business contacts, making it the perfect tool if you want to be found. How does LinkedIn work exactly? How can you use your online network to find a new job and new assignments? How do recruiters work and how can you use that knowledge to your advantage? All these questions are answered in this book. But it also offers a practical step-by-step approach for using LinkedIn in a professional way. Read this book and get immediate benefits from the wealth of knowledge inside! Aaltje Vincent is an experienced career professional and an authoritative expert in job marketing. Jacco Valkenburg is an experienced recruitment expert and a pioneer in recruiting staff via LinkedIn. He has written Recruitment via LinkedIn. </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Aaltje Vincent</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Jacco Valkenburg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bridge to Mark]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/412557509/bridge-to-mark-a-t--vergunst</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/412557509/bridge-to-mark-a-t--vergunst"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:04.414Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A412557509?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767238310082&sig=1601c0524480b2e7055bdd063e7e7770020b67177853320f9f4afce1eda611a5&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'Bridge to Mark'" title="Omslag van 'Bridge to Mark'">
<p>In Bridge to Mark, the Gospel according to Mark is connected to you. By very simply explaining what it says, I have tried to get the message as close to you as possible. The book contains short pieces to felect on. It is the message of salvation. Your pastor A.T. Vergunst, Carterton, New Zealand </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>A.T. Vergunst</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Flying Dutchman]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394840194/the-flying-dutchman-anita-verkerk</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394840194/the-flying-dutchman-anita-verkerk"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:04.937Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A394840194?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767251884530&sig=d36195cb656b2e6f9a176e3e154215ca2d6d48cce400f0228e3c2945862ff524&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'The Flying Dutchman'" title="Omslag van 'The Flying Dutchman'">
<p>Cupido Hot Romance 18+ Kelly Wilbers is about to marry handsome Ron, when she finds her husband-to-be in the arms of another woman. In shock, Kelly puts on her wedding gown and walks into the sea to finish her lousy life. But she ends up on a strange historical Three Master. A party ship? Or did she really travel in time? A spicy paranormal romance from best-selling author Anita Verkerk. The author's rights of this e-pub are protected by a watermark. </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Anita Verkerk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lord of the Marsh]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394840151/lord-of-the-marsh-anita-verkerk</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394840151/lord-of-the-marsh-anita-verkerk"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:05.398Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A394840151?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767238309932&sig=dba609a3b46319d3784753e00244616228e4d67108b063c5b77e868dab9df67f&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'Lord of the Marsh'" title="Omslag van 'Lord of the Marsh'">
<p>Cupido Hot Romance 18+ When a car crash ruins her future, Myra Parker finds herself desperately searching for happiness. In Holland, her attention is caught by mysterious disappearances and rumors of an ancient force known as the Lord of the Marsh... A sizzling paranormal tale of eternal love between husband and wife from best-selling author Anita Verkerk. The author's rights of this e-pub are protected by a watermark. </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Anita Verkerk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ice Maiden]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394840208/ice-maiden-anita-verkerk</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394840208/ice-maiden-anita-verkerk"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:05.957Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A394840208?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767251885509&sig=241bbf0a1aec246a575f8368d62e52599c8564d4efc1796804a3ae466b702b30&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'Ice Maiden'" title="Omslag van 'Ice Maiden'">
<p>Cupido Hot Romance 18+ Lizzy Rumbold is frigid and never had an orgasm. Will an ancient German relic give her the release she craves? A spicy paranormal romance from best-selling author Anita Verkerk! The author's rights of this e-pub are protected by a watermark. </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Anita Verkerk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The enchanted castle]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394840224/the-enchanted-castle-anita-verkerk</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394840224/the-enchanted-castle-anita-verkerk"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:06.497Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A394840224?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767251886072&sig=c8bdc7ce5dfb762cf4eaa021b513da528b4a8bbdab64e6ad69768167b3e873a4&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'The enchanted castle'" title="Omslag van 'The enchanted castle'">
<p>When love and passion are cast aside in favor of Michael's career, he forces Samantha to take fate into her own hands. Craving the long nights of love they used to share, she lures Michael to France to spend one scorching night in The Enchanted Castle... A spicy paranormal romance from best-selling author Anita Verkerk. The author's rights of this e-pub are protected by a watermark. </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Anita Verkerk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Mysterious Knight]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394840178/a-mysterious-knight-anita-verkerk</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394840178/a-mysterious-knight-anita-verkerk"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:06.963Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A394840178?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767238310628&sig=018ec320b639fb540b6259d246493bea47bb1f9f455bd4369d8f322837130b77&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'A Mysterious Knight'" title="Omslag van 'A Mysterious Knight'">
<p>Cupido Hot Romance 18+ Princess Esmeralda is afraid of love, and refuses to marry. A gorgeous mysterious knight saves her life, teaching her the secrets of pleasure... A spicy romance from best-selling author Anita Verkerk. The author's rights of this e-pub are protected by a watermark. </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Anita Verkerk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My sultry confessions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/382592328/my-sultry-confessions-yolinda-vixen</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/382592328/my-sultry-confessions-yolinda-vixen"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:07.534Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A382592328?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767251887076&sig=bbcf79b312612a845748ceb23137e7640141305d62a0f210b95d315450ec39ba&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'My sultry confessions'" title="Omslag van 'My sultry confessions'">
<p>Erotische schetsen en foto's.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Yolinda Vixen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quit smoking in one day]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394617053/quit-smoking-in-one-day-jan-geurtz</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394617053/quit-smoking-in-one-day-jan-geurtz"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:08.097Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A394617053?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767251887648&sig=12687c59cfce8c2c61c1dbcd0c1642d8abd1a403c11e94ef624aed484de0de0a&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'Quit smoking in one day'" title="Omslag van 'Quit smoking in one day'">
<p>"Quit Smoking In One Day" is one of the most successful books written on ending cigarette addiction. Originally published in Holland and translated into many other languages it is now available in English for the first time. Countless people have quit smoking after reading this book. If you want to quit smoking then this book will help you succeed without withdrawal symptoms, no noticeable weight gain and without using force or self discipline. A proven method used successfully for more than 15 years. </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jan Geurtz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gravity does not exist]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394690036/gravity-does-not-exist-vincent-icke</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394690036/gravity-does-not-exist-vincent-icke"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:08.635Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[a puzzle for the 21st century]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A394690036?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767251888202&sig=d0a531db3af845d551a72cfc35e1096af2f170ded8eeb965853d3c11bfa145fb&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'Gravity does not exist'" title="Omslag van 'Gravity does not exist'">
<p>Every scientific fact was born as an opinion about the unknown - a hypothesis. Opinion gradually becomes fact as evidence piles up to support a theory. But what if there are two theories, each of which has produced a myriad of things that correspond perfectly to the phenomena but can't be combined into one? One theory replaced the mystery of gravity with a precise model of space and time. The other theory replaced the mystery of matter with a description of quantum particles. As we understand our universe, we keep each in its own domain: space and time for very large things, particles for the very small ones. However, 13.8 billion years ago, those two incompatible domains belonged to a single realm. Who in the current or future generations of physicists will crack this seemingly impossible puzzle? This, contends the author, is not just a big question, but the biggest question in physics in our century. Combining Ickes's first-hand knowledge with a robust argument and intellectual playfulness, this fascinating book succeeds in making a notoriously difficult subject accessible to all readers interested in a better grasp of our universe. -Vincent Icke is professor of theoretical astrophysics at Universiteit Leiden, professor of cosmology at the University of Amsterdam, visual artist, and writer. </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Vincent Icke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The angel of Amsterdam]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394659414/the-angel-of-amsterdam-geert-mak</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394659414/the-angel-of-amsterdam-geert-mak"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:09.132Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[seven city stories]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A394659414?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767194490249&sig=00fb1b56369c301dc08f473e9a792410d4f698478f2fb01b8c90d4a71c2d8303&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'The angel of Amsterdam'" title="Omslag van 'The angel of Amsterdam'">
<p>Many people star in this Amsterdam chronicle but the one and only protagonist is the city itself. The Angel of Amsterdam combines the dissection of the Dutch capital with a series of personal portraits. It brilliantly reveals the magic, the feel, the rituals and the forgotten world behind and beneath present-day Amsterdam. This special edition of The Angel of Amsterdam offers the international audience not only stellar writing by one of the finest of Dutch authors, but also a unique glimpse into and better understanding of the fascinating city of Amsterdam. </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Geert Mak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bridge to Genesis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/392848791/bridge-to-genesis-pastor-a-t--vergunst</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/392848791/bridge-to-genesis-pastor-a-t--vergunst"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:09.612Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A392848791?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767238308360&sig=49071c4ebb1db5c69f0853b93f4d071c4717bedea82b5826728bacce10623528&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'Bridge to Genesis'" title="Omslag van 'Bridge to Genesis'">
<p>In ‘Bridge to Genesis‘ God‘s message is connected to you. By very simply explaining what it says, I have tried to get His Word as close to you as possible. The book contains short pieces to reflect on. Take time to pray that God may bless it. His message is the most important you can possibly hear or read. It is the message of salvation. Pastor A.T. Vergunst Waupun, WI, USA </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Pastor A.T. Vergunst</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The big reset]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/399312552/the-big-reset-willem-middelkoop</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/399312552/the-big-reset-willem-middelkoop"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:10.226Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[war on gold and the financial endgame]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A399312552?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767251889750&sig=44ed3054e9af396eb676dfa3f51a9fd13101bbfd294d00983bd4eead1608e863&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'The big reset'" title="Omslag van 'The big reset'">
<p>Kritische analyse van het wereldwijde financiële systeem, met een pleidooi voor grondige hervormingen.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Willem Middelkoop</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Amsterdam Tinkerbells]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394945468/the-amsterdam-tinkerbells-eric-kollen</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/394945468/the-amsterdam-tinkerbells-eric-kollen"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:10.665Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[an erotic LGBT tale]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A394945468?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767238309656&sig=492ea2c68783f492efbcb69342d31456048abaa4078198ea34159d143b1184ec&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'The Amsterdam Tinkerbells'" title="Omslag van 'The Amsterdam Tinkerbells'">
<p>Fifteen-year-old Fabian is on his way from New York to Düsseldorf with his father. When one of the passengers becomes ill, the aircraft has to land in Amsterdam, a city under the spell of the imminent Gay Pride. Together with the handsome blond doctor Rodric and the flamboyant Brazilian Rafaela, they decide to postpone their journey to Düsseldorf and instead to throw themselves into the festivities. Fabian is bursting with excitement, for the next day is his sixteenth birthday. Not just any age, but... the age of consent! He is counting down the hours to midnight. But before that happens, he and his fellow travellers are in for a number of juicy surprises… Eric Kollen’s ‘Boys’ Tales’ Until now, Eric Kollen published three volumes of his ‘Boys’ Tales’, in Dutch. His stories are exciting, scandalous, virtuoso, hilarious and sometimes even deeply moving, but above all... stimulating. And the text tingles with pleasure; it is not only the sperm that spatters from the pages, but also the mirth. About Volumes 1, 2 and 3 of ‘Boys’ Tales’: ‘I roared with laughter while my prick was rock hard. Extremely clever if you can achieve that! These stories are top class.’ – GJ Wielinga, writer and ex-porno star ‘Kollen succeeds in fascinating and surprising and the pleasure he has in writing gushes from the paper. The content is decidedly direct, and occasionally boundless. Elements of power, sadomasochism and forbidden lust predominate.’ – Magazine for Sexuology ‘Fable-like and at the same time super erotic. Eric Kollen writes well.’ – Hedy d’Ancona, former Dutch Minister of Culture </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Eric Kollen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A survey of buddhist thought]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/391047701/a-survey-of-buddhist-thought-alfred-r--scheepers</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/391047701/a-survey-of-buddhist-thought-alfred-r--scheepers"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:11.218Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A391047701?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767251890775&sig=375faf1886fb2c60e9949a134c1dd2cfffa304b7190d1227e2a3cad67e317d23&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'A survey of buddhist thought'" title="Omslag van 'A survey of buddhist thought'">
<p>General in its approach, yet penetrating, this book allows the reader to become acquainted with the highlights of Buddhist philosophy. It not only treats the ideas of the founder of the religion, but follows the development of his thought through the ages. It points out how these ideas were used by the psychologists of the Abhidharma, how they issued in the mystical conceptions of Mahayana. But before all, the book treats the more intellectual notions about time and being as found in the Madhyamaka and Yogacara, and it analyses the logic of Buddhist idealism. Then the reader leaves India and goes to China to become familiar with the epochal figures of Sengzhao and Xuanzang, learns about the Garland and Tiantai schools, and, finally, he is led through the Japanese Zen Buddhism of Dogen and Hakuin. </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Alfred R. Scheepers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ibiza's child]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/402429559/ibiza-s-child-esther-j--ending</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/402429559/ibiza-s-child-esther-j--ending"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:11.757Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A402429559?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767251891347&sig=4b42aff3b5519f9693c79c2a37e0adfdea5b5d27823145f71284adf4a64a734e&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'Ibiza's child'" title="Omslag van 'Ibiza's child'">
<p>IBIZA, THE EIGHTIES. At the dawn of the techno and ecstasy era a lonely teenager sees her world going into a tailspin. Marianne, born on the island to a hippie mother and a drug dealing father, is trying to keep the pieces of her life together while one of her parents is in prison in Liverpool and the other is chasing her spiritual endeavours. When an officer from the notorious Guardia Civil offers her a ride and shelter, Marianne becomes deeply fascinated by him. Embarking on a vodka and drug fueled journey, she tries to build a bridge between two worlds that weren't meant to meet. With her father's villa on the verge of confiscation and her mother's rickety sense of reason plummeting to unmanageable depths, Marianne's fascination for the Guardia grows into a dangerous obsession. She might well be driving not only herself but everyone close to her to the brink of destruction. IBIZA'S CHILD is a novel about obsession - blinding, all-consuming obsession - and about a desperate search for parental love, a home, a fatherland. It is also a book about Ibiza: Ibiza as only those who were born on the island or have lived there for many years can know it. A genuine, bizarre, enigmatic, magnificent, deadly, never-to-be-encapsulated Ibiza. ESTHER J. ENDING (1972) grew up on the island of Ibiza. She moved to the Netherlands permanently in 1994 and debuted in 2004 with the novel After Valentine, for which she received the prestigious Debut Prize. Her second novel Silent People came out in 2012. 'A dazzling novel straight from Ibiza's womb' THOMAS ROSENBOOM 'A revealing portrait of the dark side of Ibiza, very boldly written' JAN CREMER 'Extremely captivating and moving. Must read for everyone who loves Ibiza' SASKIA NOORT 'Fabulous novel! Absolute must read for everyone going to Ibiza' BART CHABOT </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Esther J. Ending</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The eight great beacons of cultural awareness]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/401569276/the-eight-great-beacons-of-cultural-awareness-jim-morris---sylla-pahladsingh</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/401569276/the-eight-great-beacons-of-cultural-awareness-jim-morris---sylla-pahladsingh"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:12.423Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[navigating the cultural landscape]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A401569276?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1766949496639&sig=e65a922d7d3efcaa22cb5367d6d495ffa86f35a156ae5c82d41cac3cc8b417c3&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'The eight great beacons of cultural awareness'" title="Omslag van 'The eight great beacons of cultural awareness'">
<p>The book that you are holding is the indispensable guide to cultural awareness. Are you working in an international environment, with people from different countries? Working internationally requires specific competences and relationship skills. Getting to know other cultures can be fun and enlightening. Yet, at times, you might find communication challenging and puzzling, sensing emotions and observing reactions that more often deal with the deeper level of culture. Despite our good intentions, we often struggle to communicate at that required deeper level, leading to misunderstanding and the souring of negotiations. This book is a practical guide and will strengthen your cultural awareness. Getting under the skin of other cultures (and your own!) and understanding how to make the most of diversity is a 'must-have' skill. The Eight Great Beacons help you to successfully navigate the cultural landscape and guide you on this fascinating journey. More than ever this is the book to buy if you want to improve your interpersonal relationships and international business results! Jim Morris is a senior facilitator and project manager for Schouten Global. He lives and breathes culture: English by nationality, he lives in the Netherlands and works all over the world facilitating professional learning and development. He specialises in intercultural communication training programmes. Jim grew up in the UK, where he started his career, and lived for long periods in Australia and Canada. He has worked extensively throughout Central Europe, North America and Asia, running workshops and delivering keynote speeches. Sylla Pahladsingh is an independent business communication adviser, facilitator and owner of Sylla Training & Consulting. She advises people and teams on leadership and communication issues in a cross-cultural context. Born to a Dutch mother and Surinamese-Indian father, her life has been an inspiring multicultural experience. She lived and worked as a training and capacity development consultant for 16 years in respectively Kenya, Bhutan, Vietnam and the USA. She currently resides in the Netherlands. </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Morris</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Sylla Pahladsingh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The meaning of music]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/400363445/the-meaning-of-music-leo-samama</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/400363445/the-meaning-of-music-leo-samama"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:12.933Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A400363445?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767238310134&sig=fdbebc81f8264b322e354a0920a73eaaf189956c531660280bebe5d7613f75f9&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'The meaning of music'" title="Omslag van 'The meaning of music'">
<p>For virtually all of our lives, we are surrounded by music. From lullabies to radio to the praises sung in houses of worship, we encounter music at home and in the street, during work and in our leisure time, and not infrequently at birth and death. But what is music, and what does it mean to humans? How do we process it, and how do we create it? Musician Leo Samama discusses these and many other questions while shaping a vibrant picture of music's importance in human lives both past and present. What is remarkable is that music is recognised almost universally as a type of language that we can use to wordlessly communicate. We can hardly shut ourselves off from music, and considering its primal role in our lives, it comes as no surprise that few would ever want to. Able to transverse borders and appeal to the most disparate of individuals, music is both a tool and a gift, and as Samama shows, a unifying thread running throughout the cultural history of mankind. </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Leo Samama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shoe is my middle name]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/404997570/shoe-is-my-middle-name-niels-shoe-meulman</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/404997570/shoe-is-my-middle-name-niels-shoe-meulman"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:13.505Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[written paintings and painted words]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A404997570?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767251893057&sig=63a7cd4e8bbd435ce135edd73815f0d5f1cf97b43cdbf10c5b816e7782a44ffe&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'Shoe is my middle name'" title="Omslag van 'Shoe is my middle name'">
<p>Ever since he picked the graffiti name Shoe in 1979, Niels Meulman has been carving out his own path towards the international art world. Being a graffiti pioneer from Amsterdam, he worked with American counterparts such as Dondi White, Rammellzee and Keith Haring in the 1980s.  He made the transition from the streets to fine art with a unique fusion of calligraphy and graffiti, which he named Calligraffiti. This soon became a worldwide phenomenon and now plays a significant role within Urban Contemporary Art. It also sparked the catchphrase 'A word is an image, writing is painting'.  In recent years Niels Shoe Meulman moved towards a style he calls Abstract Vandalism. Influenced by the great painters of Abstract Expressionism, his work has been shown in countless exhibitions all over the world and is included in the permanent collections of museums and private collections.  Shoe Is My Middle Name celebrates three decades of art by a legendary graffiti artist, painter, writer, designer and calligrapher. A striking book that offers an overview of his career, showcasing his evolution through a masterful mixture of paintings, murals, poetry, interviews, graphics and insights about his identity as an artist and art itself. </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Niels Shoe Meulman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Homosexuality in Africa]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/406375569/homosexuality-in-africa-bart-luirink---madeleine-maurick</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/406375569/homosexuality-in-africa-bart-luirink---madeleine-maurick"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:13.944Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[a disturbing love]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A406375569?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767238308685&sig=17541c5e6370b72e436376d5b4b0ff0bbd3f0393e27d8e3d94331e02f6be3806&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'Homosexuality in Africa'" title="Omslag van 'Homosexuality in Africa'">
<p>Plagues of locusts, drought and ebola. In Africa homosexuals are getting the blame for everything. It's open season. Homosexuality is called 'un-African', 'in direct conflict with its own distinctive culture', a 'western disease'. What's the motivation behind those leaders who are fighting to keep their continent 'morally pure'? There's another story. More and more African gays and lesbians are coming out of the closet. Equal rights activism has become a reality and a passionate debate is raging. Well-known personalities are speaking out. Anti-homosexual laws are biting the dust. Actions and reaction. Acceleration and obstruction. Shifting perspectives in a rapidly changing continent. What's the real situation? Where does the antipathy towards homosexuality come from? What's the role of religious fundamentalism? Does western interference help or hinder? Is Africa different or just the same? This book gives an illuminating insight into a world in which old and new, tradition and modernity, are colliding so uncompromisingly that the sparks have started to fly. It's unleashed a swathe of simmering tensions that has now engulfed the entire continent. Dispensing with all the platitudes and slogans, the authors uncover a conflict in which far more is at stake than just the rights of a minority. </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Bart Luirink</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Madeleine Maurick</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Art and politics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/404330290/art-and-politics-joes-segal</id>
        <link href="https://www.onlinebibliotheek.nl/catalogus/404330290/art-and-politics-joes-segal"/>
        <updated>2026-01-01T07:18:14.462Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[between purity and propaganda]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://leibniz.zbkb.nl/assets/id/PPN%3A404330290?aid=kb-online-bibliotheek&sid=19&dts=1767251894055&sig=e6dfebd1753edfa0ecb6791799618fdb673ca4d7a45b7475346298587484bd1d&width=320" alt="Omslag van 'Art and politics'" title="Omslag van 'Art and politics'">
<p>At first glance, art and politics seem like they couldn't be more separate, with politics focused on the grubbiness of everyday reality and art busily creating a fantasy world of creative expression. Yet the two realms frequently come together, and the collision can be fiery. This book explores the position of art and artists under a number of different political regimes of the twentieth and twenty-first centuries, traveling around the world to consider how art and politics have interacted and influenced each other in different conditions. Joes Segal takes us to the Third Reich, where Emil Nolde painted under pressure; shows us Diego Rivera creating Marxist murals in Mexico and the United States; ties Jackson Pollock's drip paintings to their Cold War context; and considers the countless images of Mao Zedong in China. In each case, he analyses the inherent tension between free expression and ideology, the aims of the artist and the exigencies of politics. </p><p><small>Bron: Flaptekst, uitgeversinformatie</small></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Joes Segal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>